Programming Advocate Grant Smith

Summary

An innovative and passionate programmer and teacher with experience teaching online and in-person courses. Presenter at many meetups and creator of much online content including YouTube videos, GeoGebra applets, and more. Aspiring to work in curriculum development, subject matter expertise, teaching, or developer advocacy.

Skills

Technical Python, Pandas, Tensorflow, SQL, JavaScript, LATEX, Git, Power BI, AWS, Jupyter, Excel, Julia

Content OBS, Reveal.js, YouTube, Medium, GeoGebra

Soft Skills Presenting, curruculum design, teaching, mentoring, onboarding, training, leadership, documentation, communication, teamwork, creativity, innovation

Community Engagement and Content Creation

2022–2022 **Meetup Presenter**, East Bay Machine Learning Meetup, Virtual

Has presented five times within the last year on various deep learning topics. The meetup has around 20 attendees each time, and the recordings have 600 views on YouTube.

2022–2022 Career Fair Representative, Security Benefit, Various, KS

Is the go-to representative for career fairs. Found and hired two interns, both of which we hired full-time at the end of the internships.

2022–2022 Content Creator (Personal), YouTube, Medium, Github, Kaggle, GeoGebra,

Has lightly been making Youtube videos and other content for the last 6 years. Has made 40 YouTube videos (2,000 views) and 52 GeoGebra applets.

Teaching Experience

2021–2022 Data Analytics Boot Camp Instructor, EdX / Ohio State University, Virtual

Taught an online data analytics boot camp.

- O Earned a 5 star rating from each student in both review to EdX and Rate My Professor.
- O Taught the class in the evenings while working full time.
- O Exercised autonomy and course design expertise to streamline and tailor the curriculum.
- 2022 Pre Calculus Instructor, The University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS

Taught two classes of pre-calculus at The University of Kansas.

O Earned a 5 star rating from each student – in both review to KU and Rate My Professor.

Work Experience

2022-Present Quantitative Developer, Security Benefit, Topeka, KS

Worked on our derivative valuation software.

- Initiated our documentation effort.
- Is part of our group leadership.
- O Has given many presentations on topics such as Git, deep learning, static sites for documentation.
- O Performed as mentor and onboarding guide for new hires.

- 2020–2021 **Business Intelligence Developer**, *Black and Veatch*, Overland Park, KS Developed business intelligence solutions with Power BI and other BI and data engineering tools. Was the onboarding guide and mentor to all three new hires in our group.
- 2019–2020 **Software Developer, Implementation Engineer**, Atonix Digital (Black and Veatch Subsidiary, now owned by Prometheus Group), Overland Park, KS

 Began on the implementation team to onboard new clients. Worked way into role on the development team. Was the onboarding guide/mentor/trainer to both new hires in our group
- 2016–2019 **Data Manager, Chemical Engineer**, *Black and Veatch*, Overland Park, KS Began career as chemical engineer, but fell in love with programming. Redirected career toward that goal.

Education

- 2022 **Certified Cloud Practitioner**, *AWS*, Virtual
 - Earned Amazon Web Services Cloud Practitioner Certification.
- 2022 **Mathematics, M.A.**, *The University of Kansas*, Lawrence, KS Spent a semeter as a master's student. Left early for quant opportunity.
- 2012–2016 Chemical Engineering, B.S., The University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS
 - O Business minor.
 - Leadership certificate.
 - O Was on The Dean's List for academic achievement. 3.85 GPA.
 - Was the president of his fraternity, which included managing 100+ students, 70+ of which lived in the house.

Comments From Peers

- Security O What I really appreciate about Grant is how proactive he is. Simply put, he makes problems Benefit go away.
 - I have not met a more team-first person than Grant.
 - I keep finding Grant's documentation in here and it keeps saving my butt.
- Students O Super friendly, kind, nice and caring. You can tell he truly loves what he does! Definitely recommend and take again.
 - He has an uncanny ability to sense when your ADHD brain begins to zone out and immediately refocuses the class.